【OP Theme Song】
【OP 片头曲】
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement, Mixing: Shanghai Image
作詞 作曲 編曲 混音 上海映像
Arrangement, Editing, Cinematography
編曲 編輯 攝影師
Vocals: Cinematographer
演唱 攝影師
Performance: Cinematographer
演繹 攝影師
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Spy
Mojo Spy
Let's go
Let's go
This world, a riot of color
這個世界 五彩氾濫
Truth and lies confuse our eyes
真真假假迷惑我们的眼
Use your heart to truly see
用你的心认真去看
The truth is never far away
发现真相就在不远
Hey you good or bad, truth or lies
Hey you good or bad 真真假假
Can't escape the smoky haze of the mind
逃不出这心灵的灰烟
Bring all your courage with you
带上你的所有勇敢
Maybe you can save the world
也许就能拯救这世界
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Spy
魔咒Spy
A dream that's real
真实的梦
Miss MU
小MU姐姐
I'm Jingjing, I'm such a big fan of you!
我是菁菁，我好喜欢你哦
What are you doing?
你在干嘛
Sing me a song, please.
給我唱首歌吧
Miss, I can't sing anymore.
姐姐以後不能再唱歌了
Ah, why?
啊 為什麼呀
Because I've been poisoned by a very strange curse.
因為姐姐中了一種非常奇怪的毒
Unless I untie the knot in my heart,
除非排解開我的心結
I'll never wake up again,
否則 我再也不能醒來
and never sing again.
再也不能唱歌
How do I untie your heart knot?
怎麼解開你的心結
I'll go ask my uncle for help.
我去找老舅帮忙
He's always drooling over your photo—
他經常看著你的照片流口水
he'll definitely help you!
他一定會幫你的！
Hey, little girl, I don't even know you, yet you care so much about me. Maybe in this world, only you and Wen Kang truly care. Perhaps I really can't wake up. So I'll tell you the wrong I've done. Many years ago, I wasn't a big star yet.
哎,小妹妹,我与你素不相识你却这样关心我,也许,在这个世界上,关心我的人就只有你和文康,或许我真的不能醒来了,我就把自己做过的亏心事告诉你,许多年前,那时我还不是什么大明星。
DO MI SO
DO MI SO
Xiaolu, Xiaolu
晓露 晓露
Xiaolu, you know? Tuna Town's
晓露 知道吗 金枪鱼
star variety show,
金枪鱼镇明星综艺节目
Smile Match, is holding a talent contest.
微笑对对碰正在举办选秀
Let's go together!
我们一起去参加吧
I... I don't want to go.
我 我不想去
You go instead.
还是你去吧
You're pretty and sing well—
你很漂亮 唱歌又好听
you'll definitely win the championship.
肯定会得冠军的
You're always so slow
你这样慢吞吞
Just like a clover's nature
像三叶草的性格
You never change
总是改不了
We've studied music for so long
咱们学习音乐这么久
Isn't it so more people
不就是为了更多的人
Can hear our work?
能听到我们的作品吗
What's wrong with you?
你这个人怎么这样
This is such a great chance
这是多么好的一个机会
Once we become champions
一旦成了冠军
We'll be huge stars
将来就会大红大紫
Weren't you always trying
你不是一直想给你哥哥
To lighten your brother's load?
减轻负担吗
Let's go together
我们一起去吧
Um... alright then
嗯 那 好吧
The elimination rounds are down to this
淘汰赛进行到现在
We have only two contestants left
我们只剩下两位选手
Competing for the championship throne
来竞争冠军的宝座
That's right
是的
They are the lively and cheerful
他们就是活泼开朗
Sweet-voiced Miss MU
声音甜美的小MU
And the gentle, multi-talented Xiao Lu
与性格恬静多才多艺的晓露
One week from now
一周之后
Our two contestants will perform
我们的两位选手将演唱
Their own original songs
自己原创的歌曲
In the final showdown
进行最后的决赛
The championship trophy—who will take it home in the end?
冠军奖杯最终将花落谁家呢
Let's wait and see.
让我们拭目以待吧
What do we do? What do we do?
怎么办 怎么办
Only one week left.
就剩一周了
But I just can't pick a good song.
可我却选不出一首好歌来
Miss MU, are you there?
小MU 你在吗
I'm Xiaolu.
我是晓露
I'll be right there.
我马上来
Miss MU
小MU
I just wrote a song for my brother's birthday.
我刚刚替哥哥的生日写了一首歌
I'll show it to you first.
我第一个拿给你看
From now on, you can't call me slowpoke anymore!
你以后可不许说我总是慢吞吞了
Let me take a look.
我看看
Awesome!
真好
Xiaolu, you're amazing!
晓露你真厉害
Yeah.
嗯
I'll sing this song in the finals.
我决赛就唱这首歌
It's a bit tight on time.
虽然时间有点紧
Perfect as a birthday gift for big bro!
不过刚好可以作为哥哥的生日礼物
Oh, haha, nice!
哦 哈哈 好啊
I bet your brother will be thrilled.
我猜你哥哥肯定会高兴的
Just that
只是
I think there are a few minor flaws.
我觉得有几个地方稍有瑕疵
No worries though.
不过没有关系
Let me take another look.
我再看一看
Can you pour me a glass of water?
你能帮我倒杯水吗
Sure.
好啊
I'll go get it right away.
我这就去倒水来
Xiaolu.
晓露
Sorry.
对不起
I didn't mean to.
我不是故意的
I...
我
It's okay.
没关系
It's not your fault.
不怪你
I'll just rewrite another copy.
我重新再写一份就好
Sorry.
对不起
It's all my fault.
都是我的错
Now let's invite Miss MU to sing her original song.
现在邀请小MU来演唱她的原创歌曲
Her song is...
她演唱的曲目是
Happy Birthday.
Happy Birthday
Happy birthday to you.
祝你生日快乐
No way, I don't know.
不会的 不知道
Miss MU wouldn't do this.
小MU不会这么做的
I'm dreaming.
我是在做梦
I must be dreaming.
我一定是在做梦
Sis.
妹妹
What's wrong with you?
你这是怎么了
That's my song!
那是我的歌!
It was a birthday gift for you, big brother.
是送给哥哥你的生日礼物
Miss MU sang my song.
小MU唱了我的歌
What do I do?
怎么办
She's my best friend.
她是我最好的朋友
Thank you.
谢谢
I really regret it now.
我现在真的好后悔
If only
如果
I could start over,
可以重新来过
I would treasure my friendship with Xiaolu.
我一定会珍惜和晓露的友情
Xiaolu...
晓露
I truly, truly regret it.
我真的真的好后悔
Don't worry, Miss MU.
小MU姐你别着急
Jingjing makes mistakes too,
菁菁也经常做错事
and gets scolded by Locky Qi.
被齐乐天骂
You already know you did wrong.
你已经知道自己做错了
Xiaolu will forgive you.
晓露一定会原谅你的
Wake up! Wake up! Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
醒醒 醒醒 醒醒 醒醒 醒醒
So lazy, still sleeping!
这么懒还在睡
You're supposed to be watching a patient,
明明是在看护病人
but you sleep more than anyone.
却睡得比谁都多
Get up!
起来！
Xiaolu will forgive you.
晓露会原谅你的
Xiaolu...
晓露
Who is Xiaolu?
晓露是谁啊
Looks like Miss MU's condition hasn't improved.
看来小MU的病还是没有什么起色
I'll come back later to check on her.
那我稍晚再过来探望吧
Any progress?
有什么进展吗
After investigation,
经过调查
the two girls who presented flowers during the performance
演出当天献花的那两个女孩
had paint on their faces
之所以在脸上涂抹油彩
because they just came from a friend's birthday party
是因为刚刚参加过朋友的生日派对
and hadn't washed it off yet
还没来得及洗去
before attending Miss MU's concert.
就来参加小MU的演唱会了
As for the man in the mask,
而那个戴口罩的男人
he had a severe cold
是因为身患重感冒
but really liked Miss MU,
但又十分地喜欢小MU
so he attended the concert despite being sick.
才带着重病去参加演唱会
None of them could be suspects.
他们几个都不可能是嫌疑犯
Maybe we should change our angle
也许我们该换个角度
and start considering people close to Miss MU.
从小MU身边的人开始考虑
This one's not it, that one's not it either.
这个也不是 那个也不是
Who is the real culprit?
到底谁才是犯人呢
Uncle,
老舅
I think that Song Wen Kang from earlier is suspicious.
我觉得刚才那位宋文康很可疑
He has no relation to Miss MU,
他与小MU非亲非故
yet he came to visit her in the middle of the night—
却半夜来探望小MU
that's already suspicious enough.
这已经很可疑了
Plus, just now—
再加上刚刚
He suddenly left the ward in a hurry.
他突然迅速地离开病房
I'll come back to visit later then.
那我稍晚再过来探望吧
All of this is highly suspicious.
这所有的一切都让人怀疑
Locky Qi makes a good point.
齐乐天说得有道理
Why don't we go together now
不如我们现在一起去
and investigate this person.
调查一下这个人
【ED Ending Theme】
【ED片尾曲】
Tomorrow waves to me on the horizon.
明天 在你平线向我招手
Every day in sunrise and sunset,
每天就在日升日落
turning into time, dreaming more.
转进时间幻想更多
Expecting every second, every moment in life.
期待生命中 每秒每一刻
Bright eyes are sparkling,
明亮的眼睛在闪烁
facing the sun with a smile.
迎着阳光的笑容
It's not sneaky, just at the corner ahead.
它不悄悄就在前家的路口